Guide to the Cleanth Brooks Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1928-86; Series II; 26.5; (64 boxes)
  - BOOKS
    - An Approach to Literature
      - Sophomore Poetry Manual (original title)
        - Printed version, copy I, 1936 (Box 31, Folder 603)
        - Printed version, copy II, 1936 (Box 32, Folder 604)
        - Photograph negatives, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 605)
      - Fourth edition (regular)
        - Drafts, typescript, original and carbon, corrected (Box 32, Folder 606)
        - Drafts, typescript, original and carbon, corrected, parts I-II (Box 32, Folder 607-08)
        - Poetry section, draft (Box 32, Folder 609)
        - Drama section, drafts (Box 32, Folder 610)
        - Notes, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 611)
      - Fourth edition (alternate)
        - Theater of the absurd, early drafts, parts I-II, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 612-13)
        - Theater of the absurd, notes and drafts, parts I-II (Box 32, Folder 614-15)
        - Theater of the absurd, galley proofs, corrected, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 616)
        - Appendix
          - Early drafts, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 617)
          - Galley proofs, corrected, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 618)
        - Drama section, page proofs, corrected, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 619)
        - Proofs, pp. 1-362, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 620-31)
        - Proofs, pp. 295-872, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 632)
        - Correspondence with publisher, 1962-74, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 633-36)
        - Comment cards, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 637-38)
      - Fifth edition
        - Contents, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 639)
        - Preface, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 640)
        - Introduction, typescript, photocopies, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 641)
        - Professor's version, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 642)
        - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 643)
        - Galley proofs, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 644)
        - Page proofs, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 645)
        - Notes on An Approach to Literature [complimentary booklet], advertisement, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 646)
        - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 647)
          See also: Box 96, folder 2003
    - Fundamentals of Good Writing
      - Book reviews, 1950-52 (Box 34, Folder 648)
    - The Hidden God
      - Research notes, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 649)
      - Yeats: drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 650)
      - Hemingway: drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 651)
      - Eliot: drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 652)
      - Faulkner: drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 653)
      - Auden and Warren: drafts, typescript, corrected (Box 35, Folder 654)
      - Warren: drafts, typescript, corrected (Box 35, Folder 655)
      - Page proofs, 1963 (Box 35, Folder 656-57)
      - Book reviews, 1963-64 (Box 35, Folder 658)
      - Correspondence, 1956-67, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 659)
    - The Language of the American South
      - Ch. I, "Where It Came From": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 660)
      - Ch. II, "The Language of the Gentry and the Folk"
        - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 661)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 662)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 663)
        - Draft D, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 664)
      - Ch. III, "The Language in the Present Day"
        - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 665)
        - Draft B, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 666)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 667)
      - Chs. I-III: typescript, corrected, with printer's annotations, 1985 (Box 35, Folder 668-70)
    - Literary Criticism
      - Research material, 1956 (Box 35, Folder 671)
      - Research material and draft fragments (Box 35, Folder 672)
      - Tragedy and Comedy (Chapter 25)
        - Research material and draft fragments (Box 36, Folder 673)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 674)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 675)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 676)
        - Draft D, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 677)
        - Draft E, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 678)
      - Symbolic Form (Chapter 26)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 679)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 680)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, 1956 (Box 36, Folder 681)
        - Draft D, typescript carbon, corrected, 1956 (Box 36, Folder 682)
      - Richards chapter (Chapter 27)
        - Draft A, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 683)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 684)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 685)
        - Draft D, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 686)
        - Draft E, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 687)
        - Draft F, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 688)
        - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 689)
      - Semantics [second Richards chapter] (Chapter 28)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 690)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 691)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 692)
        - Draft D, typescript, corrected, ca. 1956 (Box 37, Folder 693)
        - Draft E, typescript carbon, corrected, ca. 1956 (Box 37, Folder 694)
      - Eliot and Pound (Chapter 29)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 695)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, ca. 1956 (Box 37, Folder 696)
        - Draft C, typescript carbon, corrected, ca. 1956 (Box 37, Folder 697)
      - Fiction introduction: draft fragments, typescript, corrected (Box 37, Folder 698)
      - Fiction and Drama (Chapter 30)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1955 (Box 37, Folder 699)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1956 (Box 38, Folder 700)
        - Draft C, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 701)
      - Myth and Archetype (Chapter 31)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, ca. 1954 (Box 38, Folder 702)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, ca. 1956 (Box 38, Folder 703)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, ca. 1956 (Box 38, Folder 704)
        - Draft D, typescript carbon, corrected, ca. 1956 (Box 38, Folder 705)
        - Draft E, typescript carbon, corrected, ca. 1956 (Box 38, Folder 706)
      - Epilogue ("Some Recent Developments") (Chapter 32): typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 707-08)
      - Book reviews, 1957-58 (Box 38, Folder 709)
      - Correspondence with publisher, 1946-63, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 710)
      - Correspondence re permissions, 1956-58, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 711-12)
    - Modern Poetry and the Tradition
      - "An Apology for Intellectual Poetry"
        - Ch. I, "Definition of the Conceit": typescript and carbon, corrected, ca. 1934 (Box 38, Folder 713)
        - Ch. II, "The Conceit in Elizabethan Poetry": typescript and carbon, corrected, ca. 1934 (Box 38, Folder 714)
        - Ch. III, "The Conceit in Metaphysical Poetry": typescript, corrected, ca. 1934 (Box 38, Folder 715)
        - Ch. IV, "Metaphysical Poetry": typescript, corrected, ca. 1934 (Box 38, Folder 716)
        - Ch. V, "The Augustans and the Search for Sublimity": typescript and carbon, corrected, ca. 1934 (Box 38, Folder 717)
        - Ch. VI, "The Fancy and the Imagination": typescript and carbon, corrected, ca. 1934 (Box 38, Folder 718)
        - Ch. VII, "The Modern Conceit": typescript carbon, corrected, ca. 1934 (Box 38, Folder 719)
        - Ch. VIII, "A New History of English Poetry": typescript and carbon, corrected, ca. 1934 (Box 38, Folder 720)
        - Appendix A, "The Meaning of the Term The Metaphysical Poets (Box 38, Folder 721)
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, ca. 1934
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, ca. 1934 (Box 38, Folder 722)
          - Draft C, typescript carbon, corrected, ca. 1934 (Box 38, Folder 723)
          - Draft D, typescript, corrected, ca. 1934 (Box 39, Folder 724)
        - Appendix B, "Symbol and Conceit: A Note on Axel's Castle ": typescript and carbon, corrected, ca. 1934 (Box 39, Folder 725)
      - "The Poetry of Tiresias"
        - Preface, Chs. I and II: typescript, corrected (Box 39, Folder 726)
        - Chs. III and IV: typescript, corrected (Box 39, Folder 727)
        - Chs. V and VI [published as VII] (incomplete): typescript, corrected (Box 39, Folder 728)
        - Chs. VII [published as VIII] (incomplete) and VIII [published as IX]: typescript, corrected (Box 39, Folder 729)
        - Ch. IX [published as X]: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 730)
      - "The Anatomy of Modern Poetry"
        - Preface, Chs. II and III: typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 39, Folder 731)
        - Chs. IV, VI and VII: typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 39, Folder 732)
        - Chs. IX and X: typescript carbon, corrected (Box 39, Folder 733)
      - Paperbound edition, "A Retrospective Introduction": typescript carbon, corrected, 1966 (Box 39, Folder 734)
      - Book reviews, 1939-66, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 735)
      - Correspondence (Box 39, Folder 736)
    - Modern Rhetoric
      - Third edition
        - Part one, typescript, corrected, with printer's annotations, pp. 1-150, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 737-39)
        - Part one, typescript, corrected, with printer's annotations, pp. 151-289, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 740-42)
        - Part three, typescript, corrected, with printer's annotations, pp. 1-550, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 743-52)
        - Part three, typescript, corrected, with printer's annotations, pp. 551-579, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 753)
        - Part three [variant draft], typescript, photocopied and printed version, corrected, with printer's annotations, pp. 253-375 (Box 41, Folder 754-56)
        - Research material and notes, 1968-69 (Box 41, Folder 757)
        - Front matter and indexes
          - Draft A, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 41, Folder 758)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, with printer's annotations, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 759)
        - Ch. IX
          - Draft A, typescript, photocopied, corrected, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 760)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 761)
        - Ch. X, printed version and typescript, photocopied, corrected (Box 41, Folder 762)
        - Ch. XI, printed version and typescript, photocopied, corrected (Box 41, Folder 763)
        - Ch. XII, printed version and typescript, photocopied, corrected (Box 41, Folder 764)
        - Ch. XIV, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 765)
        - Ch. XV
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 766)
          - Draft B, typescript, photocopied, corrected, with printer's annotations, 1969 (Box 41, Folder 767)
          - Draft C, typescript, photocopied, corrected, with printer's annotations, 1969 (Box 42, Folder 768)
        - "Readings," typescript carbon and photocopied, corrected, with printer's annotations (Box 42, Folder 769)
        - "Manual for Latter Part of the Readings," typescript, photocopied, corrected, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 770)
        - Appendix, typescript carbon, corrected (Box 42, Folder 771)
        - Graphics, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 772)
        - Galley proofs, corrected, 1969 Dec 4 (Box 42, Folder 773-79)
        - Galley proofs, corrected, 1969 Dec 4 (Box 43, Folder 780-84)
        - "Instructor's Manual"
          - Typescript carbon, corrected, with printer's annotations, pp. 1-200, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 785-88)
          - Typescript, photocopied, corrected, with printer's annotations (incomplete), 1970 (Box 43, Folder 789)
          - Page proofs, photocopied, corrected, with printer's annotations (Box 43, Folder 789)
          - Warren copy, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 790)
          - Brooks copy, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 791)
          - Tackett copy, 1970 (Box 44, Folder 792)
          - Page proofs, photocopied [unmarked copy], 1970 (Box 44, Folder 793)
          - Page proofs, photocopied [unmarked copy] (incomplete), 1970 (Box 44, Folder 794)
      - Fourth edition
        - Galley proofs, corrected (incomplete), n.d. (Box 44, Folder 795)
        - "Manual for Modern Rhetoric "
          - Research material and draft fragments, parts I-III (Box 44, Folder 796-98)
          - First draft, typescript, corrected, parts I-III, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 799-801)
      - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 802)
      - Correspondence, 1969-76 (Box 44, Folder 803)
    - Poems of Mr. John Milton
      - Book reviews, 1952-53 (Box 44, Folder 804)
    - A Shaping Joy: Studies in the Writer's Craft
      - Introduction: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 805)
      - Ch. 6, "Poetry and Poeticality"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 806)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 807)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 808)
        - Draft D, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 809)
        - Draft fragments, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 810)
      - Ch. 12, "The Southern Temper":
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 811)
        - Draft B, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 812)
        - Draft C, typescript, photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 813)
      - Ch. 13, "Southern Literature: The Wellspring of Its Vitality": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 814)
      - Ch. 17, "Edgar Allen Poe as an Interior Decorator": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 815)
      - Galley proofs, parts I-IV, ca. 1971 (Box 45, Folder 816-19)
      - Published book: corrected for second edition, 1971 (Box 45, Folder 820)
      - Dust jackets, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 821)
      - Advertisements, 1972 May 18 (Box 45, Folder 822)
      - Book reviews, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 823)
    - Tragic Themes in Western Literature
      - Book reviews, 1955-56 (Box 45, Folder 824)
    - Understanding Drama
      - Draft: typescript, corrected, parts I- III (Box 45, Folder 825-27)
      - Advertisements, 1947 Mar (Box 45, Folder 828)
    - Understanding Fiction
      - Fourth edition
        - Revision, draft fragments, holograph and photocopy of printed text (Box 45, Folder 829)
        - Advertisements, 1959, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 830)
        - Book reviews, 1958 (Box 45, Folder 831)
        - Correspondence, 1978-79, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 832)
        - "Description of Understanding Fiction ," typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 45, Folder 833)
        - "Manual for Understanding Fiction ": typescript, photocopy, corrected, pp. 1-149 (Box 46, Folder 834-36)
    - Understanding Poetry
      - Fourth edition
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 837-38)
        - Typescript, corrected, with printer's annotations [acknowledgments, preface, contents], n.d. (Box 46, Folder 839)
        - Preface, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 840)
        - Introduction material, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 841)
        - Introduction material, typescript, corrected, photocopy, with printer's annotations, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 842)
        - Early text with corrections, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 843)
        - Sections I and II, early drafts, typescript, corrected (Box 46, Folder 844)
        - Section III, early drafts, typescript and holograph, corrected, parts I-II (Box 46, Folder 845-46)
        - Section III, obsolete copy, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 847)
        - Section V, typescript, corrected, parts I-II, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 848-49)
        - Section V, with R.P. Warren's revisions, typescript, photocopy, parts I-II, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 850-51)
        - Section V, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 852)
        - Section VII, preliminary notes, typescript and photocopy, corrected (Box 47, Folder 853)
        - Discards, typescript, corrected, parts I-III, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 854-56)
        - Discards, R.P. Warren's copy, typescript, photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 857)
        - Reader's report, 1975 Jul 14 (Box 47, Folder 858)
        - Final draft, typescript, corrected, with printer's annotations, pp. 1-300, 1975 (Box 47, Folder 859-64)
        - Final draft, typescript, corrected, with printer's annotations, pp. 301-925, 1975 (Box 48, Folder 865-76)
        - Final draft, typescript, corrected, with printer's annotations, index of authors, titles, and terms, 1975 (Box 48, Folder 877)
        - Galley proofs, corrected, with printer's annotations, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 878-86)
        - Galley proofs, corrected (incomplete), n.d. (Box 49, Folder 887)
        - Mechanicals
          See: Box 93, folder 1990
        - Page proofs, corrected, parts I-II, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 888-89)
        - Notes on taping the conversation between Frost, Ransom, Lowell, and Brooks and Warren (Box 49, Folder 890)
        - Transcription of conversation between Frost, Brooks, and Warren
          - Typescript, mimeograph, corrected, first draft, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 891)
          - Typescript, mimeograph, corrected, second draft (Box 50, Folder 892)
          - Typescript, mimeograph, corrected, third draft, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 893)
          - Typescript, mimeograph, excisions, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 894)
        - Transcription of conversation between Ransom, Brooks, and Warren
          - Typescript, mimeograph, corrected, first draft, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 895)
          - Typescript, mimeograph, corrected, second draft (Box 50, Folder 896)
          - Typescript, mimeograph, excisions, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 897)
        - Transcription of conversation between Lowell, Brooks, and Warren
          - Typescript, mimeograph, first draft, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 898)
          - Typescript, mimeograph, corrected, second draft (Box 50, Folder 899)
          - Typescript, mimeograph, excisions, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 900)
        - Prepared statement of Roethke: typescript, mimeograph, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 901)
        - Publicity, 1960, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 902)
        - Advertisements, 1950 (Box 50, Folder 903)
        - Book reviews, 1940-66, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 904)
        - Correspondence, 1972, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 905)
      - Instructor's Manual
        Second edition
        - Sections I-VI, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 50, Folder 906)
        - Sections I-IV, typescript, copies I-II, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 907-08)
        - Notes re revisions, 1973 (Box 50, Folder 909)
        - Research notes and early drafts, parts I-III (Box 50, Folder 910-12)
        - Research notes and early drafts, part IV (Box 51, Folder 913)
        - Fourth edition
          Early draft
          - Introduction material, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 914)
          - Section I, research material, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 915)
          - Section I, typescript, corrected, parts I-II, 1973 Dec 10 (Box 51, Folder 916-17)
          - Section I, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 918)
          - Sections II, IV, and V, typescript and carbon and photocopy, corrected, parts I-IV (Box 51, Folder 919-22)
          - Section III, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 923)
          - Sections IV and V, notes, holograph and typescript and photocopy, parts I-II (Box 51, Folder 924-25)
          - Section VI, typescript, photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 926)
          - Section VII, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 927)
          - Section VII (early version of "Birds" with Red's notes on it), typescript, photocopied, corrected, parts I-II, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 928-29)
          - Intermediate draft, typescript, photocopy, corrected, parts I-V, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 930-34)
          - Final draft, typescript, corrected, with printer's annotations, pp. 1-361, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 935-41)
    - The Well Wrought Urn
      - Draft: typescript, corrected, pp. 1-150 (Box 52, Folder 942-44)
      - Draft: typescript, corrected, pp. 151-314, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 945-47)
      - Ch. II: typescript, corrected, parts I-II (Box 53, Folder 948-49)
      - Draft fragments: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 950)
      - Page proofs: London ed. with author's, printer's, and editor's corrections, 1968 Mar 25 (Box 53, Folder 951)
      - Correspondence with publisher, 1945-67, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 952)
      - Book reviews, 1947-65 (Box 53, Folder 953)
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 953a)
    - Wm. Faulkner: First Encounters
      - Preface
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, ca. 1983 (Box 53, Folder 954)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, ca. 1983 (Box 53, Folder 955)
      - Final draft, typescript, corrected, with printer's annotations, pp. 1-297, 1983 (Box 53, Folder 956-61)
    - Wm. Faulkner: Toward Yoknapatawpha and Beyond
      - Ch. I, "Faulkner's Poetry"
        - Draft A, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 54, Folder 962)
        - Draft B, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 54, Folder 963)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 964)
        - Draft D, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 965)
      - Ch. II, "Early Romantic Prose"
        - Draft A, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 54, Folder 966)
        - Draft B, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 54, Folder 967)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 968)
      - Ch. III, "A Payment Deferred" ( Soldiers' Pay )
        - Draft A, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 54, Folder 969)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 970)
      - Ch. IV, "Sketches, Early Stories, and an Abortive Novel"
        - Draft A, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 54, Folder 971)
        - Draft B, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 54, Folder 972)
      - Ch. V, "A Fine Volley of Words" ( Mosquitoes )
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 973-75)
        - Draft A, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 54, Folder 976)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, photocopy, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 977)
      - Ch. VII, "People Without a Past" ( Pylon )
        - Draft, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 54, Folder 978)
      - Ch. VIII, "A Tale of Two Innocents" ( The Wild Palms )
        - Draft A, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 55, Folder 979)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 980)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 981)
      - Ch. IX, "Man's Fate and Man's Hope" ( A Fable )
        - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 982)
        - Draft B, printed version, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 983)
      - Ch. X, "Faulkner on Time and History"
        - Draft, typescript, photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 984)
      - Appendix B, "The Narrative Structure of Absalom, Absalom! "
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 985)
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 986)
      - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 987-92)
      - Page proofs, corrected (incomplete), n.d. (Box 55, Folder 993)
      - Publicity, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 994)
      - Book reviews, 1963 (Box 55, Folder 995)
    - Wm. Faulkner: The Yoknapatawpha Country
      - Table of contents, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 56, Folder 996)
      - Ch. I, "Faulkner the Provincial"
        - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 997)
      - Ch. II, "The Plain People: Yeoman Farmers, Sharecroppers, and White Trash"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 998)